export const questions4 = [
  {
    question: 'What type of fuel is commonly used in liquid rocket engines?',
    options: [
      'Solid gel',
      'Liquid oxygen and liquid hydrogen',
      'Gas fuel',
      'Biofuel',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Liquid oxygen and liquid hydrogen',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which of the following technologies allows to reduce the weight of the rocket?',
    options: [
      'Use of composite materials',
      'Increasing the size of the engine',
      'Reducing the number of degrees',
      'Application of metal structures',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Use of composite materials',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What technology is used to control the trajectory of a rocket during flight?',
    options: [
      'Gyroscopic stabilization',
      'Water draft',
      'Pneumatic systems',
      'Magnetic fields',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Gyroscopic stabilization',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of these elements is the main part of a rocket engine?',
    options: [
      'Body',
      'Traction mechanism',
      'Combustion chamber',
      'Management systems',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Combustion chamber',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What system provides cooling of the engine during its operation?',
    options: [
      'Liquid cooling',
      'Air cooling',
      'Convection cooling',
      'Thermal conductivity',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Liquid cooling',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which of these technologies allows rockets to be reused?',
    options: [
      'Solid fuel engines',
      'Liquid fuel engines with multiple uses',
      'Parachute systems',
      'Hypersonic technologies',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Liquid fuel engines with multiple uses',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which of the following components is part of the missile control system?',
    options: ['Missile case', 'Engine', 'Fuel', 'Navigation system'],
    correctAnswer: 'Navigation system',
  },
  {
    question: 'What technology allows rockets to reach high speeds?',
    options: [
      'Solid fuel engines',
      'Liquid rocket engines with afterburner',
      'Hydraulic systems',
      'Electric motors',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Liquid rocket engines with afterburner',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is a "stage" in the context of rocketry?',
    options: [
      'Part of the rocket responsible for navigation',
      'Engine cooling system',
      'The time during which the engine is running',
      'A detachable part of a rocket that has its own engine',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'A detachable part of a rocket that has its own engine',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which of these technologies is the most promising for future space missions?',
    options: [
      'Solid rockets',
      'Nuclear heat engines',
      'Rockets on electric traction',
      'Chemical missiles',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Rockets on electric traction',
  },
];
